Edward Ascan

Junior software developer with a background in SaaS sales. Passionate about web development processes, learning, and building challenging applications. Previously I worked as a Business Development Representative for a software company and have recently decided to pivot my career and learn how to build software myself. As a recent bootcamp graduate, I'm a quick learner, with strong communication, time management and collaborative skills and I excel in fast-paced environments.

PROJECTS

Hoolu

Developed a single-page application clone of Hulu, that uses TMDB API to show a server-side rendered catalog of popular movies based on different categories. This application was developed with the intent of learning basics of Next.js and Tailwind CSS, as well as to practice utilizing external APIs.

Front-end: ReactJS, Next.js, HTML, Tailwind CSS.

LinkedIn Clone Mini

Developed a single-page application (SPA) mini clone of LinkedIn, using ReactJS, Redux and Firebase authentication and storage, with the intention of further developing React knowledge, learning introductory Redux and Firebase. This application allows users to register, login and create posts on the main feed.

Front-end: ReactJS, Redux, HTML, CSS.

Back-end: Firebase

Yalper

Developed a single page application (SPA) using ReactJS, NodeJS & ExpressJS, which also implements Google Oauth and Cloudinary APIs, to allow users to provide services & regular users to find service providers for their specific needs.

Front-end: ReactJS, Axios, HTML, SASS. **Back-end**: NodeJS, ExpressJS, PostgreSQL.

Interview Scheduler

Developed Interview Scheduler - a single page application (SPA) built using ReactJS. This application allows users to book and cancel interviews.

Front-end: React|S, HTML, SASS.

Back-end: NodeJS, ExpressJS, PostreSQL.

Testing: Jest, Storybook, Cypress.

Mapple

Developed Mapple - a multipage, fullstack application that saves and manages maps and map locations with tags for users. Maps are organized by interest and can be edited, organized and favourited.

Front-end: Javascript, Ajax, JQuery, HTML, SASS.

Back-end: NodeJS, ExpressJS, PostreSQL.

www.edwardascan.com Toronto, ON edward.ascan@me.com 416-669-7278

Github

https://github.com/eascan
LinkedIn
https://www.linkedin.com/in/edwardascan/

SKILLS

Languages: Javascript, Ruby, HTML. CSS.

Frameworks, libraries & environments: NodeJS, ReactJS, Next.js, Ajax, Axios, Rails, JQuery, Bootstrap, SASS, Tailwind CSS, Cypress, Jest, Mocha & Chai, Storybook.

Systems & Databases: SQL, PostreSQL, Git, ActiveRecord.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Sales Development Representative

Synapse, Toronto, 2019-2020.

Account Manager & Business Development

Flow Water, Toronto, 2018-2019.

Personal Trainer

GoodLife Fitness, North York, 2017-2018.

EDUCATION

Lighthouse Labs, Fullstack Web Development Diploma, Toronto, 2021

Queen's University, Bachelor of Science, Kingston, 2016 **St. Andrew's College**, Ontario Secondary School Diploma, Aurora, 2011

LANGUAGES

Bilingual: English & Russian.